Guide to the Printmaker File [1730]-2014, undated (bulk 1800-1860) PR 58
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Prints 16 x 20" and smaller
  - Falconer, John Mackie (1820-1903)
    - The Earliest Art Centre in New York City, No. 180 Fulton St., AD 1816, et. seq." [The Parker Clover], 1880 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
      2 copies
    - First Methodist [Sanctuary] in New York City, 1880 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [House Where Robert Fulton Served his Apprenticeship], 1893 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - 53 Maiden Lane [in]1842, Where Salmagundi was Published 1819" [J. Bucklass Tailor Shopfront], 1880 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [North Dutch Church, Corner of William and Fulton], 1882 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
  - Farrer, Henry
    - "The Old Beach House Cor. Cedar & Greenwich, 1816 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [On New York Bay], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
  - Fernbach, Agnes B. (b. 1876)
    - A Bit of the Harlem River, 1922 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
      printed by Ernest Roth
    - [Across Central Park Lake], 1929 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Across Central Park Lake, 1929 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [Boat houses along Hudson River], 1920 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [City Tree], 1932 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Cove, Central Park, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Gregorian Door, Jumel Mansion, 1921 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Organ & Choir, Old Temple Emanu-El, N.Y., undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [Soldiers' and Sailors' Monument], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [Tree at Riverside], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - [Synagogue interior], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
  - Fiene, Ernest (1894-1965)
    - ['L' Train, baths, and barber shop](41/50), 1933 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
  - Flanagan, Albert (1886-1969)
    - Afternoon Light, N.Y.C., 1930 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - The Church Missions House, New York: the World Headquarters of the Episcopal Church, 1932 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y., 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Dusk - William St., 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - The Fountain. Central Park - N.Y., 1933 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Harbor Sunset, N.Y., 1934 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Jacob Street, N.Y., 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Manhattan - The City of Towers, 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Manhattan Shore - East River N.Y., 1930 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Morning Light, N.Y., 1934 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Night- New York, 1932 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Skyline-N.Y., 1933 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Storm at Sunset, 1932 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Towers of Manhattan - 42nd Street Group, 1930 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Towers of Manhattan - 57th Street Group, 1930 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Plaza Group - Towers of Manhattan, 1930 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Wall Street Group - Towers of Manhattan, 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
    - Waterfront, New York, 1933 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
  - Flotten, Cy
    - Brooklyn Bridge, 1935 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box F)
  - Gayler, Julius F. (1872-1948)
    - The Eternal Light New York, 1935 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
      aquatint
    - First Jewish Cemetery, 1934 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - Grace Church, 1938 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - "House of Lenox Mass 1936" [Winthrop House, designed by Gayler] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
      etching
    - MacDougal Alley, 1936 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - Municipal Center, 1937 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - New York Doorway [15 E. 81st], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - New York Water Front [beginning of steel work for Empire State Building], 1930 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - New York Water Front, 1938 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - New York Water Front, 1939 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - [Old House Near East Haddam Connecticut], 1938 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - [Old Mill Western Massachusetts], 1935 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - "Peacock" [Grounds of Grenville L. Winthrop House, Lenox, Massachusetts], [1936] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - Saint Paul's Church, New York (proof), 1938 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - Saint Paul's Church, New York (final take), 1938 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - Washington Square South, 1936 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
  - Glover, De Lay (ca. 1823-ca. 1863)
    - "The Summer Dream", undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - "The Empty Cradle", undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - "The Evening Star", undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - [William Shakespeare], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - [Oliver Goldsmith?], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - [two untitled scenes, two untitled portraits, a printer's trade card, and two vignettes], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
  - Grant, Gordon (1875-1962)
    - "Fog Over Gloucester", undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
  - Gregory, Frank M. (1848-?)
    - [Grace Church], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
    - Twenty-Third St., Fifth Ave & Broadway, 1887 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
      etching on silk
  - Gross, Chaim (1904-1991)
    - [Design to commemorate the 100th anniversary of laying the cornerstone of Central Synagogue in New York City], 1971 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box G)
      lithograph, impression 22 of 120
  - Hall, Charles B.
    - Block House and Gate, Foot of Wall St., undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Old House, corner Broad and Exchange Place, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hanley, Frank
    - Jefferson Market Clock, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
      block print
  - Haskell, Ernest (1876-1925)
    - Birth announcement of Haskell's daughter Hildegarde, 1910 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Greeting Card, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Holiday Card, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - "In memorium" for Elizabeth Louise, Haskell's first wife, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Wedding announcement for Haskell's second marriage to Emma Loveland, 1920 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Birth announcement for twins Ernest jr. and Josephine, 1921 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hassam, Childe (1859-1935)
    - [New York Stock Exchange Floor], 1927 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Henry, J.
    - "Water Mill" [Nyack], 1880 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Heriot, George (1766-1844)
    - [Bordeaux, France], after 1816 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hewitt, Edward S. (1877-1962)
    - Coal and Barges, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - [East River Skyline], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - [Midtown Towers, Waldorf Astoria], 1877 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Tugs and Towers, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hoff, Henry
    Includes "Views of New-York," 1850, color lithographs
    - "Astor Place Theatre" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "University" [Washington Square] (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Niblo's Hotel" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Grace Church" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Union-Square, Bird's Eye View" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Stewart's Buildings and Broadway" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "New-York from Governor's Island" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "City Hall of Brooklyn" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
      after C. Autenrieth
    - "Castle Garden" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Hospital of Brooklyn" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Odd Fellows Hall" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Croton Water Reservoir" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "City Hall" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Tombs" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Custom-House" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
      after C. Autenrieth, published by Hoff & Bloede
    - "Exchange" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "Institution for the Blind" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
    - "St. Paul's Church, Barnum's Museum and Astor House" (Offsite-box Hoff, Henry. Views of New York, Folder unknown container)
  - Hoover, Ellison (1888-1955)
    - [Washington Square Arch in winter], [1920-1930] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hoppe, F. Werner (active ca. 1920-1930)
    - [Washington Square Arch], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hunt, Leigh (1858-1959)
    - Hell Gate Bridge, 1917 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - Washington Bridge, 1896 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Hunter, F[rederick] Leo (1862-1943)
    - Coenties Slip, South Street, 1881 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - [Equitable Building], unadted (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - [Grace Church], 1903 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - N.Y. Produce Exchange, 1887 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
    - The Old New York University Building, 1878 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
  - Jacobi, Eli (1898-1984)
    - At Sharkey's, 1939 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box H)
      Linocut. Purchase, 1986. See also N-YHS collection of prints from the Works Progress Administration, Federal Arts Project (PR 345) for a Jacobi print.
  - Jones, Eugene Arthur (b. 1881)
    - [Express Office, Fulton Market], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box J)
    - [Pier 18- Fulton Market], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box J)
  - Kangman, Edwin
    - Brooklyn Bridge, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
  - Kent, Rockwell
    - Starry Night, 1933 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
      Wood engraving. Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Kerr, Robert (1823-ca.1904)
    - "The Customs House, Wall Street, Viewed from Broad Street", 1845 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
      hand-colored lithograph after his own design, view No. 1 in "Views of New-York by Robert Kerr, architect"
  - King, L.H.
    - The Little Church Around the Corner, 1897 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
  - Kingman, Dong (1911-2000)
    - "New Dawn, 1984 FAO World Food Day" (767/1000) (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
      General Note
      lithograph after watercolor (print and printed envelope)
  - Kohler, William (fl. 1830s-1840s)
    - [Ship labelled in gold as "Victoria"] sailing away full sail, bearing the Royal Standard and the Union Jack. The largest sail lifts as a flap to reveal portrait of Queen Victoria, bust length to right, wearing crown and ermine. Published by C. Tilt, Fleet Street., 1837 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
  - Koslow, Howard (b. 1924)
    - The Bridge (36/100), 1983 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box K)
  - Landeck, Armin (1905-1984)
    - Manhattan Nocturne, 1938 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      drypoint
  - La Paglia, Anthony
    - "Seascape Series #3", [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 8 of 100.
    - "Landscape Series #2", [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 7 of 50.
    - "Landscape Series #3", [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 5 of 50.
    - [Snowscene], [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper
    - [Still life], [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 21 of 37.
    - [Fish], [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
    - [Birds], four different prints, [1930-1949] (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
  - Levine, Martin (b. 1945)
    - 42nd & 5th, 1998 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
  - Lewis, Martin (1882-1962)
    - Chance Meeting, 1940 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Drypoint etching
    - Boss of the Block, 1939 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
      Aquatint and etching, 11"x 15.5". Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Lowell, Nat (1880-1956)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge and lower Manhattan from Brooklyn], 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
    - Home of New York Chemical Mfg Co. 1824 [Tenth Ave.], undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
    - UN Headquarters, undated (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
    - [Washington Bridge, New York], 1931 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
  - Lubbers, Adriann (1892-1954)
    - Brooklyn Bridge (55/68), 1929 (Offsite-box Box F-L, Box L)
  - Marsh, Reginald (1898-1954)
    - People's Follies, 1938 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
      Etching. Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Meissner, Leo (1895-1977)
    - Bleecker Street Follies (22/30), 1927 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
      linoleum cut
    - Journal Square, Jersey City (9/30), 1925 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
  - Meyerowitz, William (1887-1981)
    - Grant's Tomb, 1919 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Modern New York, 1933 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - New York No. 1, or, 59th St. Bridge, 1931 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - On the Hudson, 1918 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Passing the Arch of Victory, 1919 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
  - Mielatz, Charles Frederick William (1864-1919)
    - A Bit of Baxter Street, undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - [Aaron Burr's House, 11 Reade Street], 1898 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - [Astor House], 1910 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Catherine Market with Brooklyn Bridge, 1903 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Cherry Street, 1904 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Coenties Slip, 1907 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Colonnade Lafayette St. de Milhaus Home, 1907 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - The Dewey Arch, 1900 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - [Dutch Reformed Church], 1898 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Elevated Station at Night, undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Entrance to Brooklyn Bridge, 1892 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - In the Bowery, undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Jumel Mansion in Winter, 1911 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Lych Gate: Little Church around the Corner, [1902-1906] (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - No. 7 State Street, 1908 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Old Door on Houston Street, 1903 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Old Tom's on Thames Street, [1902-1906] (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Oyster Market, Foot of Christopher St., 1903 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Rainy Day Broadway, 1892 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Rainy Night, Madison Square, 1890 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Restaurant in Mott Street, 1906 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Seaman's Church Institute on State Street, 1909 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - [Wall Street, looking west to Trinity Church], undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - Washington Square, 1908 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
    - [Windmill], 1887 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
  - Milbert, Jacques Gerard (1766-1840). A Series of Picturesque Views in North America, Paris, 1825
    Lithographs.
    - "1st View of McComb's Mill's on the River Harlem near King's Bridge" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "2nd View of the River Harlem" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Mr. McComb's House on the River Harlem near King's Bridge" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "McComb's Bridge Avenue" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of the Tavern on the Road to King's Bridge near Fort Washington" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Front View the Fortifications at Harlem near [the city of] New-York" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Mr. Van Den Heuvel's Country Seat" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Spiten Devil's Creek" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Bridge on the Croton 40 Miles N. of New-York" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of the Fall on Bronx River Lydich's Mill West Farms" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of Flushing (Long Island), North America. Oak-trees, under which George Fox, quaker, preached the Truths of the Gospel" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of Flushing (Long Island), North America. Mr. Bowne's House. It remains in the possession of his family ever since 1661 time when it was built." (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      3 copies
    - "View of Lydick's Mill & House on Bronx River, West Farms" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
  - Milbert, Jacques Gerard (1766-1840).Itineraire pittoresque du fleuve Hudson et des Parties laterals, 1828-1829
    - "Interior of New-York, Provost Street and Chapel" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis Villeneuve, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 3
    - "Tarry-town where Major Andre was Captured" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 4
    - "Sing-Sing or Mount Pleasant" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 5
    - "Haverstraw or Warren Landing" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 6
    - "Lower Falls near the Residence of Mrs. Montgomery" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis Villeneuve, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 10
    - "Town of Hudson" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, Plate 11
    - "View of Hudson & the Catskill Mountains" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 12
    - "Albany-Capital of the State of New-York" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Isidore-Laurent Deroy, Plate 13
    - "The Spot where General Burgoyne surrendered to General Gates" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 17
    - "General View of the Hudson at Adley's" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Julien Lacottet, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 29
    - "Falls on the Genesee Rivers" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Francois-Joseph Dupressoir, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 37
    - "Military Post. Sacketts Harbor" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Jean Louis Tirpenne, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 39
    - [Black River Near Lake Ontario] (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Barnet & Doolitt, Plate 40 [ca. 1821-1822]
    - "Machine for the Portage on the Susquehanna" (Offsite-box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, Plate 51
  - Mohn, Siguard M. (b. 1891)
    - [St. Paul's Chapel, Broadway, N.Y.] (3/50), undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
  - Moskowitz, Ira (1912-2001)
    - 4 etching: [A Day in Central Park], [Brooklyn in Winter], Central Park, Long Island Countryside, 1920's, undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
      etchings
  - Murphy, Bill (b. 1952)
    - From Silver Lake (34/50), 1999 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box M)
  - Nelson, George Laurence (1887-1978)
    - [Still life], 1942 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box N)
      lithograph presented to members of the Allied Artists of America
  - Newton, Edith (1878-1964)
    - "Marion's Dolls", 1937 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box N)
  - Noual, J. (fl. 1761 to ca. 1790s)
    - "A View of Bethlehem, one of the Brethren's Principal Settlements, in Pennsylvania, North America,", undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box N)
      hand-colored line engraving after Nathaniel Garrison, printed for Robert Sayer, London
  - Northcote, Stafford M.
    - "Tong Yin Yee Schung Gun", undated (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box N)
      proof wood engraving, after his own design, printed on tissue
  - Opper, Frederick Burr (1857-1937)
    - A Hint to the Hebrews- how they may make themselves independent of the watering place hotels, 1881 (Offsite-box Box M-O, Box O)
      color lithograph cartoon from Puck, (11 May 1881. p.178)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
      gift of Eric Zafran, 2016
  - Pantell, Richard (b. 1927)
    - The Five Points, 1985 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Valentine Avenue, 1984 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Wishing Well, artist's proof, 1980 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Parish, Betty Waldo (1908-1996)
    - Bleecker Street, 1938 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Doyer Street (3/10), 1936 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      etching and engraving
    - East of Gramercy (3/19), 1951 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Encroachment of a City (8/25), 1952 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      copper engraving
    - 14th Street & 5th Avenue, 1936 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Gay Street (12/22), 1937 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Grove and Bedford, 1937 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Marketing on Avenue A, 1936 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - The Park from the Plaza (6/23), 1946 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      etching, engraving, and aquatint
    - Remembrance of Things Past (4/25), 1953 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Third Avenue and 11th Street (13/20), 1936 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Thompson Street, 1938 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - 2 West 15th St., 1950 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Washington Square South (11/31), 1939 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Patterson, Charles Robert (1878-1958)
    - Ship "Bangalore" at South St., 1898, 1948 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Pendleton's Lithography, William S. and John B. Pendelton
    - "The Toilet", undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - "Henry Costar's Hat Warehouse", 1831 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      drawn by A. J. Davis
  - Pennell, Joseph (1857-1926)
    - Fifth Avenue Building, undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - [Streetscape], undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      See also: Series II
  - Perard, Victor (1870-1957)
    - Looking Up Broadway New York From No. 1 B'way, 1909 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - The Old Hansom Cab, 1904 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      soft ground etching
    - "Sketch Class, Provincetown Mass.", 1940 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - "Tending Nets, Cape Cod Mass.", 1941 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Petrulis, Alan (b. 1954)
    - City of Ships (30/100), undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - White Street (30/100), 1977 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Platt, C.A. (1861-1933)
    - Shanties on the Harlem, [1880] (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Platt, Peter, J.
    - King Bridge, N.Y., 1917 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
      after a painting by C. A. Platt, 1884
    - Old Lorillard Snuff Mill, Bronx River, 1912 (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Plowman, George T. (1869-1932)
    - Capt. Adrian Van Brunt Homestead, Brooklyn N.Y. (3/50), undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Capt. Jan Schenck Homestead, Brooklyn N.Y. (3/50), undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)